Chris Reynolds

cpreynolds@outlook.com 07939528710 @cprenno

Personal Statement

An IT professional with experience in project management and application support. I have excellent communication, presentation and organization skills, and a professional attitude in the workplace. My experience managing development teams in the public and private sectors will prove invaluable.

Work Experience

Head of Digital Production - Apr 2016 to Present

Tokyo Liverpool

Tokyo is a leading Full Service Digital Agency based in London and Liverpool. They create digital products for all sizes and shapes of clients across the technology spectrum, specialising in beautifully designed high traffic high profile websites, CMS platform delivery for multinational pharmaceutical firms, and product development using bleeding edge technology.

Responsibilities

- Managing the project delivery team in the Liverpool Studio
- Scheduling work and managing project change
- Agile and Prince2 Practitioner
- Waterfall and Agile project management as appropriate
- Oversight of client management and communications
- Managing project budgets and standardizing documentation processes across retained and project based clients
- Requirements gathering, proposal writing and attending pitches
- Managing teams of remote workers and contractors

Project Manager - October 2014 to Mar 2016

Digital Services
Liverpool City Council

The Digital Services team provides solutions to improve service delivery for Liverpool City Council's public access channels and support digital applications used in the public and private sector.

Responsibilities:

- Managing the transition from Liverpool Direct Limited back to Liverpool City Council
- Agile and Prince2 Practitioner
- Waterfall and Agile project management as appropriate
- Kick off meetings with clients and creating project scope/SORs
- Managing project budgets and documenting projects (SOR/PID/RAG/Plans)
- Ensuring that organizational channel shift will lead to increase in digital service delivery
- Managing teams of developers and designers
- Managing change in the ICT environment
- Deploying third party systems
- Standardizing internal project processes and creating a sustainable project framework
- Scheduling of development time and ensuring delays or change requests in projects have minimal impact to the development schedule

Digital Project Manager - Feb 2014 to May 2014

Rippleffect

Liverpool

Rippleffect is an award winning Digital Agency owned by Trinity Mirror PLC. The projects team deliver a variety of showcase sites, content managed solutions and applications. These are produced for a variety of clients including retailers, football clubs, public bodies and large companies.

Responsibilities:

- Prince2 Practitioner
- Manage a portfolio of high profile clients
- Lead internal and external teams through the project delivery cycle, from scoping to handover.
- Scoping, planning and specifying projects, managing them effectively within timings and to budget.
- Build relationships with clients and be the main point of project contact, managing expectations and driving internal resource, clients and third party suppliers to ensure deliverables are on time.
- Create and maintain effective project documentation
- Fundamental understanding of Project Management processes and methodologies.
- Excellent verbal and written communication and ability to lead multiple projects simultaneously.
- Understand technologies applicable to projects and facilitation of the resolution of technical issues.

Project Manager - November 2012 to Feb 2014

Digital Services
Liverpool Direct Limited
Responsibilities:

- Agile and Prince2 Practitioner
- Waterfall and Agile project management as appropriate
- Kick off meetings with clients and creating project scope/SORs
- Managing project budgets and documenting projects (SOR/PID/RAG/Plans)
- Ensuring that organizational channel shift will lead to increase in digital service delivery
- Managing teams of developers and designers
- Managing change in the ICT environment
- Deploying third party systems
- Scheduling of development time and ensuring delays or change requests in projects have minimal impact to the development schedule

Geodata Technician and Project Support - February 2009 to November 2012 Geodata and Digital Services Liverpool Direct Limited

The Geodata team are responsible for managing Liverpool City Council's access to spatial data, supporting MapInfo GIS, analyzing, cleaning and matching large data sets and providing an online geospatial service to Liverpool City Council.

Responsibilities:

- Management and maintenance of the Local Land and Property Gazetteer
- Liaison between a wide range of services within LCC
- Improving data quality and synergy between service areas
- Processing of data within GIS programmes
- Advanced MapInfo user
- Management of ISO9001 core processes and quality assurance processes
- Supporting Digital project managers with internal and external projects

GIS Technician - October 2007 to December 2007

Projects and Planning Team Lancashire County Council Environment Directorate

I gained work experience within this team as a GIS technician. My duties included using ArcView to present spatial data, create maps and base plans. These were used by planners, designers and architects to visualize projects to be carried out locally. The environment directorate works toward improving communities and create higher quality of life for residents. Social deprivation is a big factor in choosing locations for these projects.

A full employment history is available on request

Education

Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt

The Knowledge Academy, Manchester

Umbraco Level 1 Practitioner

Percipient Studios, Manchester

DSDM Agile Practitioner – Dec 2014 (Valid until Dec 2019)

Datrix Training, Liverpool

PRINCE2 Practitioner – June 2012 (Valid until May 2017)

Datrix Training, Liverpool

BSc, Physical Geography with Management (2:1) - September 2005 - June 2008

Edge Hill University, Ormskirk

Personal Interests

Cyclist – I started cycling to save money and keep fit on my commute but found that it is a great hobby and enjoy road biking in the UK and abroad, and now race and train with Liverpool Century Road Club.

Dog Walker – I enjoy the routine and time out of the house whatever the weather with my 3 ex-racing greyhounds.

References

Chris Garrett - Technical Director, Tokyo, Liverpool chrisg@tokyo.uk

Dan James - Creative Director, Tokyo, Liverpool dan@tokyo.uk

Will Costello – Head of Digital Services, Liverpool City Council, Liverpool william.costello@liverpool.gov.uk

Phil Williams – Senior Technical Consultant, Rippleffect, Liverpool pwilliams@rippleffect.com